A Guide to the Papers of Rita Mae Brown 1929-2001
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Rita Mae Brown 1929-2001
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12019
This collection consists of ca. 31,550 items (188 Hollinger boxes, 78 linear feet).
Sharon Defibaugh, David Patch, and Perry Still
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were purchased from Jerry N. Showalter, Ivy, Virginia, on July 2, 2001.
Biographical/Historical Information
Rita Mae Brown was born in Hanover, Pennsylvania, on November 28, 1944, and was adopted by Ralph and Julia Ellen (Buckingham) Brown. Her family moved to Florida when she was eleven, and she graduated from Fort Lauderdale High School in 1962. She attended the University of Florida, Broward Junior College (A.A. in 1965), New York University (B.A. 1968), and the Institute for Policy Studies, Washington, D.C. (Ph.D. 1976).
While chiefly identified as a writer, especially as the author of the groundbreaking and successful novel Rubyfruit Jungle(1973), featuring the lesbian character, Molly Bolt, Rita Mae Brown is also known as a political activist, feminist, speaker, and founder of such groups as the Redstockings Radical Feminist Group, National Gay Task Force, the National Women's Political Caucus, and co-founder of Radical Lesbians and Lavender Menace. She is also a co-founder with Charlotte Bunch of an experiment in communal living in Washington, D. C. called the Furies Collective, and an early member of NOW.
For more information about Rita Mae Brown and her work, consult the following sources: her memoir, Rita Will(1997); Rita Mae Brown in Twayne's United States Authors Series, by Carol M. Ward (1993); Gale Literary Databases Contemporary Authors(2001); three folders of curriculum vitae and biographical entries in Box 178 of this collection; interviews with Rita Mae Brown found in Boxes 107 and 108; entries in Who's Who in America and Who's Who in the World; and her personal website.
Scope and Content Information
This collection comprises the papers of writer Rita Mae Brown (1944-), of Nelson County, Virginia, ca. 31,550 items (188 Hollinger boxes, 78 linear feet), ca. 1929-2001, and undated, and includes manuscripts of her novels and other books, poetry, articles, mysteries, book reviews, screenplays and teleplays; fan mail, personal, family and professional correspondence; calendar diaries, personal journals, photographs, and memorabilia items; legal papers; and other miscellaneous subject files, reflecting her interest in her farm, polo, film, foxhunting, feminist and gay rights issues, and her school and college years.
The bulk of her collection primarily consists of the typescripts of her books, arranged by title; screenplays and teleplays, both original scripts and rewrites; and other literary works such as articles, short stories, book reviews, interviews with Brown and examples of her early poetry, some of which was published in Songs to a Handsome Woman and The Hand That Cradles a Rock. These have been arranged in Series I: Literary Papers and Manuscripts.
Unfortunately, complete manuscripts for some of her early and best known work are not present. The titles of works not represented in this collection of papers include: Rubyfruit Jungle, Starting From Scratch, Sudden Death, In Her Day, and The Plain Brown Rapper.
With the publication of Wish You Were Here in 1990, Brown began writing in a new genre, co-authoring with her cat Sneaky Pie a new mystery series set in Crozet, Virginia, that has proved popular and enduring. This series of books is well represented in the manuscripts series.
Manuscripts for almost all of her screenplays and teleplays are present in the collection and represent a significant part of her work. Rita Mae Brown earned a Cinematography Degree in 1968 from the New York School of Visual Arts. She was nominated for an Emmy for Best Variety Show on Television and received the Writers Guild of America Award for Best Variety Show on Television, both for "I Love Liberty" in 1982. Her work on "The Long Hot Summer" ganered her a nomination for an Emmy for Best Mini-Series, 1985. She has authored scripts for ABC, NBC, CBS, FOX Network, Walt Disney, Showtime, 20th Century Fox, Hallmark, and Alvin Cooperman Productions, among others.
The second series includes several subseries of correspondence. The greeting cards and fan mail are arranged chronologically, as are the many requests for Rita Mae Brown for public appearances and speeches, donations of money and goods, and comments regarding other authors' work for book blurbs or publicity. Some requests for Brown's participation generated enough material that either she or the processor has placed it in an individual folder under the name of the event, following the routine request folders.
Her personal correspondence is also arranged chronologically and includes the years from 1966 until today. Because of the amount of material, frequency of correspondence, name recognition, or because Brown had a separate folder for some correspondents, the processor has set up a subseries of folders devoted to individual correspondents, found in boxes 153-164. No claim is made that this is a complete or exhaustive list of important or notable correspondents. This separate subseries includes correspondence with her publishers Rowohlt, Ballatine Publishing Group and Bantam Dell Publishing; other authors; family members, such as her aunt and uncle, Jeun and Claude Brown; her aunt Mary Dundore, and her mother, Julia Brown, both of whom form the basis for the sisters in her novels, Bingo" and Six of One; film producers and entertainers; other feminists; friends; her agents, Stu Robinson and Wendy Weil; political figures; athletes; and artists. A complete list of these individuals can be found in the folder listing.
The third series contains calendar diaries; a journal kept by her mother, Julia Brown, about Rita Mae Brown as a small child; early journals kept by Rita Mae Brown, 1975-1983; memorablilia; photographs of Rita Mae Brown and her family and friends; many of various pets and animals; foxhunting and others sporting events.
The last series consists of various subject and legal files, including her work in the film industry, contracts and agreements about her books, curriculum vitae and biographical information, Farmington and Oak Ridge Hunt Clubs, horse-related business interests, polo clubs and associations, royalty statements, high school and college papers, notes, report cards, and diplomas, and legal papers involving Martina Navratilova, Judy Nelson, Julia Penelope, Josie Martin, Diana Press, and her properties in Los Angeles, Albemarle County, Virginia, and Nelson County, Virginia.
Organization
Series I: Literary Papers and Manuscripts
Subseries A: Book Manuscripts and Typescripts by Rita Mae Brown, arranged by Title (Boxes 1-68)
Subseries B: Screenplays and Teleplays by Rita Mae Brown (Boxes 69-104)
Subseries C: Articles and Book Reviews written by Rita Mae Brown, Interviews with Brown, and other Literary Work by her (Boxes 104-108)
Subseries D: Literary Work by Other Authors (Boxes 108-112)
Series II: Correspondence
Subseries A: Greeting Cards and Fan Mail (Boxes 113-131)
Subseries B: Request for Appearances, Comments, Donations, etc. (Boxes 131-139)
Subseries C: Personal (Boxes 139-152)
Subseries D: Individual Correspondent Folders (Boxes 153-164)
Series III: Calandar Diaries, Journals, Memorabilia, and Photographs (Boxes 165-175)
Series IV: Legal and Subject Files (Boxes 176-188)
Contents List
- Literary Papers and Manuscripts
  - Book Manuscripts and Typescripts by Rita Mae Brown
    All material is in typescript form unless otherwise noted.
    Arranged by Title
    - Alma Mater Orginal First Draft, with author's changes and corrections 1999 Aug 7, 434 pages; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Alma Mater, Orginal First Draft, with author's changes and corrections 1999 Aug 7, Electrostatic Copy; 434 pages; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Alma Mater First Draft, Clean Copy 1999 Aug 7, 239 pages; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Alma Mater, with author's changes and corrections, missing Chapter 14 [2000?], 351 pages; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Alma Mater, with author's changes and corrections, includes Chapter 14 [2000?], 1 of 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Alma Mater, with author's changes and corrections, includes Chapter 14 [2000?], 2 of 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Alma Mater, with editor's correspondence re the typescript, from April 2001 [2000 Oct 10], 239 pages, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Bingo First Draft 1987 Aug 7, 345 pages; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Bingo First Draft, with author's changes and corrections [1987 Aug 7], 286 pages; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Bingo First Draft, with additional author's changes and corrections [1987 Aug 7], 377 pages; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Bingo Second Draft 1987 Nov 28, 472 pages; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Bingo Setting Copy ca. 1988, 473 pages, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Bingo Setting Copy ca. 1988, Electrostatic Copy, 473 pages; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Bingo, Page Proof, with artist's map and a letter 1988 Apr 25, Electrostatic Copy (Box 6)
    - Bingo--Book Tour and Book Cover 1988-1989 (Box 6)
    - Bingo--Book Tour (Paperback) 1989 (Box 6)
    - Bingo--Notes 1988 Feb and n.d. (Box 6)
    - Bingo--Research ca. 1978-1987 (Box 6)
    - Bingo--Reviews 1988 (Box 6)
    - Cat on the Scent Original Draft with author's changes and corrections 1997 Jan, 312 pages; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Cat on the Scent Original Draft with author's changes and corrections 1997 Jan, Electrostatic copy, 262 pages only (1 of 2 folders) (Box 6)
    - Cat on the Scent Original Draft with author's changes and corrections 1997 Jan, Electrostatic copy, 262 pages only (2 of 2 folders) (Box 7)
    - Cat on the Scent Original Draft with author's changes and corrections [1997 Jan], Second electrostatic copy, 262 pages only; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Cat on the Scent First Draft 1998 Feb 9, Line-edited manuscript, 363 pages; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Cat on the Scent Second Draft 1998 Apr, 294 pages; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Cat on the Scent Copy Editor Copy, with Notes from Beverly Lewis 1998 Jul 1, 293 pages, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Cat on the Scent, with editor's corrections n.d., 290 pages; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Cat on the Scent n.d., 290 pages; 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Cat on the Scent--Book Covers, Illustrations and Notes 1998-1999 (Box 8)
    - Cat on the Scent--Book Tour and Reviews 1999 (Box 8)
    - Cat on the Scent--Illustrations 1998 (Box 8)
    - Catch as Cat Can First Draft, with author's changes and corrections 1999 Apr 16, 307 pages, 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Catch as Cat Can, with author's changes and corrections 1999 Jun 21, 343 pages; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Catch as Cat Can, with author's changes and corrections 1999 Jun 30, 343 pages; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Catch as Cat Can, Clean Copy 1999 Jun 30, 343 pages; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Catch as Cat Can, with author's changes and corrections n.d., 378 pages; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Catch as Cat Can, with editor's changes and comments n.d., 381 pages; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Claws and Effect First Draft 1998 Oct 20, 287 pages; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Claws and Effect First Draft, revised by author [ante 1999 March], 296 pages, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Claws and Effect 1999 Mar 3, 308; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Claws and Effect Second Copy, slightly revised 1999 Mar 3, 308 pages; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Claws and Effect, with editor's comments 2000 Apr 24, 308 pages; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Claws and Effect, Setting Copy 2000 Nov 13, 321 pages, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Claws and Effect--Dust Jacket 2000 (Box 12)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War First Draft Original 1990, 535 Pages; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War First Draft, Mid-Edit [ca. 1990 Feb], Pages 1-192 and 154-185 (Box 13)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Edited First Draft 1990 Mar 5, Pages 1-201 (Box 13)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War First Draft, Pre-Final Edit [1991], Pages 1-481; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War First Draft, Final Edit Copy [1991], 551 pages, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War First Draft [1991], Electrostatic Copy, 239 pages (Box 15)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madision in Love and War First Draft Final [1991], 562 pages, 3 folders (Box 15)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War First Draft Final, Second Copy [1991], 562 pages; 1of 3 folders (Box 15)
      formerly housed in a notebook
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War [1991], 562 pages; 2 of 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Second Draft 1991 May 23, pages 92-192, and miscellaneous pages (Box 16)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Second Draft, with author's changes and corrections and editor's comments 1991 May 23, 562 pages; 3 of 4 folders (Box 16)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Second Draft, with author's changes and corrections and editor's comments 1991 May 23, 562 pages; 1 of 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Second Draft, Clean Copy, and Bibliography 1991 May 23, 638 pages; 4 folders (Box 17)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War, Foreword 1991 Sep (Box 17)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Revised Second Draft, Beverly Lewis Edit Copy 1991 Sep 4, 625 pages; 1 of 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Revised Second Draft, Beverly Lewis Edit Copy 1991 Sep 4, 625 pages; 3 of 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Third Draft 1993 Jun 24, 560 pages; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Final Changes, Miscellaneous Pages 1993 Jun 24 (Box 18)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Third Draft Edit, In House [1993 Jun], 275 pages; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War"Original Version" for Third Draft 1993 Jun, 638 pages; 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Third Revision, Second Run Through After 1st Set Changes 1993 Jun, 251 pages; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Revised Prologue, Foreword, Acknowledgement 1993 Aug (Box 20)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Third Draft, Edit Copy by Beverly Lewis, with Brown's Changes for the Fourth Draft 1993 Aug 20, 560 pages, and additional pages 1-244 in the last two folders; 4 of 5 folders (Box 20)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Third Draft, Edit Copy by Beverly Lewis, with Brown's Changes for the Fourth Draft 1993, 560 pages, and additional pages 1-244 in the last two folders; 1 of 5 folders (Box 21)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Fourth and Final Draft 1993 Aug 27, 592 pages; 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Third Draft, Final Edit Copy 1993 Aug 28, 1 of 4 folders (Box 21)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Third Draft, Final Edit Copy 1993 Aug 28, 3 of 4 folders (Box 22)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Setting Copy 1994 Jun, 4 folders (Box 22)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War Page Proofs, 1st Pass 1994 Nov 15, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Bibliography 1991 (Box 23)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Book Covers 1994 (Box 23)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Book Tour 1994 Apr-Sep, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Correspondence 1988, 1993-1994 (Box 23)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Research Articles ca. 1990-1991 (Box 23)
      re the Madisons, originally published 1838-1991
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Research Articles, etc. ca. 1990 (Box 23)
      re John Randolph of Roanoke and the Randolph Family, orginally published 1834-1988
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Research Articles n.d. (Box 24)
      re the Capitol and the War of 1812
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolly Madison in Love and War--Research Articles 1988, n.d. (Box 24)
      re Other Characters
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Research Notes 1988-1990, n.d., 4 folders (Box 24)
    - Dolley A Novel of Dolley Madison in Love and War--Reviews and Publicity 1994 (Box 24)
    - High Hearts[First Draft], with author's changes and corrections [1984?], 805 pages; 4 folders (Box 25)
    - High Hearts[First Draft], with author's changes and corrections [1984?], 805 pages, electrostatic copy; 2 of 5 folders (Box 35)
    - High Hearts[First Draft], with author's changes and correction [1984?], 805 pages, electrostatic copy; 3 of 5 folders (Box 26)
    - High Heart First Draft Revised [early 1985?], 388 pages; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - High Hearts"Foreword" First Draft and Other Revisions [ca. 1985 Mar 14] (Box 27)
    - High Hearts Clean Copy [ca. 1985 Mar 14], 865 pages; 6 folders (Box 27)
    - High Hearts Part II Clean Copy [ca. 1985 Mar 14], Electrostatic copy, pages 305-719; 1 of 2 folders (Box 27)
    - High Hearts Part II Clean Copy [ca. 1985 Mar 14], Electrostatic copy, pages 305-719; 2 of 2 folders (Box 28)
    - High Hearts Part I Clean Copy [1985 Jun], 300 pages; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - High Hearts, with editor's comments and changes 1985 Jun 24, 382 pages; 3 folders (Box 28)
    - High Hearts Draft with editor's comments [ca. 1985 Jun], 865 pages; 5 folders (Box 29)
    - High Hearts Second Edited First Draft, Miscellaneous Pages with editor's notes 1985 Jul 12, Electrostatic copies (Box 29)
    - High Hearts Clean Copy, with Dedication to Mlle. Subertova [ca. 1985 Oct ?], 698 pages, 5 folders (Box 30)
    - High Hearts Clean Copy, with Dedication to Claude Brown [ca. 1985 Oct ?], 698 pages; 2 of 5 folders (Box 30)
    - High Hearts Clean Copy, with Dedication to Claude Brown [ca. 1985 Oct ?], 698 pages; 3 of 5 folders (Box 31)
    - High Hearts Setting Copy [1985] Oct 15, 3 of 5 folders (Box 31)
    - High Hearts Setting Copy [1985] Oct 15, 2 of 5 folders (Box 32)
    - High Hearts Part III n.d., pages 297-685; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - High Hearts Miscellaneous Pages n.d. (Box 32)
    - High Hearts--Book Tour 1986 Jan-Apr, 2 folders (Box 32)
    - High Hearts--Book Tour Correspondence and Notes 1985 Dec-1986 (Box 33)
    - High Hearts--Correspondence 1985 (Box 33)
      re the Novel
    - High Hearts--Diary 1984 Sep 1-19 (Box 33)
    - High Hearts--Notes and Proposal n.d. (Box 33)
    - High Hearts--Promotional Material and Reviews 1986 (Box 33)
    - High Hearts--Research Articles ca. 1984-1985 (Box 33)
      re Battles and Warfare
    - High Hearts--Research Articles ca. 1984-1985 (Box 33)
      re the Confederate Soldier
    - High Hearts--Research Articles ca. 1984-1985 (Box 33)
      re Medicine and Slave Narratives
    - High Hearts--Research Correspondence 1983-1985 (Box 33)
    - High Hearts--Research Notes ca. 1984-1985 (Box 33)
    - High Hearts--Research--Weather 1984 (Box 34)
    - High Hearts--Research--Women in the Civil War 1987-1994 (Box 34)
    - In Her Day Printed Pages (only) 1976, Pages 57-68 (Box 34)
    - Loose Lips Original Draft, with author's changes and corrections 1995 Oct 17, 601 pages; 4 folders (Box 34)
    - Loose Lips, with author's corrections and changes [ca. 1998?], Missing chapters 7-12, includes Pages 1-50, 93-457; 4 folders (Box 35)
    - Loose Lips, with editor's comments and changes [ca. 1998?], Some electrostatic copy, 634 pages; 2 of 4 folders (Box 35)
    - Loose Lips, with editor's comments and changes [ca. 1998?], Some electrostatic copy, 634 pages; 2 of 4 folders (Box 36)
    - Loose Lips, Clean Copy with some corrections, Parts I and II [ca. 1998], 323 pages; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Loose Lips, Page Proofs, First Pass 1999 Jan 7, 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Loose Lips n.d., Chapters 1-5, 7-12 and Pages 1-45 and 54-96, and miscellaneous other pages (Box 37)
    - Loose Lips--Book Cover, Promotional Material, and Reviews 1999 (Box 37)
    - Murder at Monticello First Draft, with author's changes and corrections [ca. 1992], 237 pages; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Murder at Monticello First Draft Original Revised Prior to Submitting to Editor 1992 Oct 14, 235 pages; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Murder at Monticello First Draft--Proofed [1992 Oct], 235 pages; 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Murder at Monticello First Draft--Revised Original 1992 Oct 14, 266 pages; 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Murder at Monticello Edit/Proof 1993 Jun 29, 279 pages; 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Murder at Monticello First Draft Revised 1993 Jul 4, Electrostatic copy, 279 pages; 2 folders (Box 38)
    - Murder at Monticello Page Proofs, First Pass, Mass Market Edition 1995 Apr 29 (Box 38)
    - Murder at Monticello--Book Cover and Illustrations 1993-1995 (Box 38)
    - Murder at Monticello--Correspondence 1994-1995 (Box 39)
    - Murder at Monticello--Promotional Material and Reviews 1994-1995 (Box 39)
    - Murder at Monticello--Research 1992-1994 (Box 39)
    - Murder on the Prowl Original Draft with author's changes and corrections 1996 Jan 16, 336 pages; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Murder on the Prowl First Draft 1996 Jan 16, 406 pages; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Murder on the Prowl, with editor's changes and notes 1997 Jul, 412 pages; 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Murder on the Prowl, with author's changes and corrections 1997 Jul, 357 pages; 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Murder on the Prowl Copy-Edited Second Draft 1997 Jul, 362 pages; 3 folders (Box 41)
    - Murder on the Prowl Second Draft, with additional changes by the author 1997 Aug 11, Electrostatic Copy, 312 pages; 3 folders (Box 41)
    - Murder on the Prowl--Artwork by Wendy Wray 1996 (Box 41)
    - Murder on Prowl--Dust Jacket and Reviews 1998 (Box 41)
    - Murder, She Meowed Original Draft, with author's changes and corrections [1994], 275 pages, 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Murder, She Meowed Original Draft, with author's changes and corrections [1994], Electrostatic copy, 275 pages; 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Murder, She Meowed First Draft, Clean Copy 1994 Dec 12, 338 pages; 2 folders (Box 42)
    - Murder, She Meowed First Draft, Edit 1994 Dec 12, 337 pages; 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Murder, She Meowed Second Draft 1996 Feb 12, 353 pages; 2 folders (Box 43)
    - Murder, She Meowed, Setting Copy 1996 Dec, 354 pages; 2 of 3 folders (Box 43)
    - Murder, She Meowed, Setting Copy 1996 Dec, 354 pages, 1 of 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Murder, She Meowed--Book Covers and Illustrations 1996 (Box 44)
    - Murder, She Meowed--Book Tour and Reviews 1996 (Box 44)
    - Murder, She Meowed--Correspondence 1996 (Box 44)
    - Outfoxed[First Draft?] with author's changes and corrections 1997 Nov 10, 418 pages; 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Outfoxed[Second Draft?] with author's changes and corrections [ca. 1998?], 419 pages, 2 of 3 pages (Box 44)
    - Outfoxed[Second Draft?] with author's changes and corrections [ca. 1998?], 419 pages; 1 of 3 folders (Box 45)
    - Outfoxed, with author's and editor's changes and corrections, and a letter with editor's comments [1999 Apr 20], Electrostatic copy, 418 pages;3 folders (Box 45)
    - Outfoxed--Book Tour 1999-2000 (Box 45)
    - Outfoxed--Dust Jackets 1999 (Box 45)
    - Outfoxed--Reviews 1999-2000 (Box 45)
    - Pawing Through the Past[First Draft?] with author's changes and corrections [ca. 1997?], 297 pages; 2 folders (Box 45)